PAUL D QUINONES

Game Developer

Austin, TX - (646) 369-6235 - PAULDQUINONES@GMAIL.COM

https://www.linkedin.com/in/pauldquinones-software-engineer/ - https://www.pauldquinones.com/



PROFESSIONAL PROFILE:

A game developer with over five years of professional programming experience in User Interface, Unity, and C#. Professional experience includes developing games and 3D design applications for mobile, desktop, and web. Over four years of Games QA experience working on over 20 shipped games across mobile, PC, and console. Won awards for Best Pitched Game for Indie Game Academy (2023), Best Game at Location(2010), UI/UX 2nd Place(2023), and Highest APM for Development(2019).

AREAS OF EXPERTISE





















PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

Gameplay Engineer / **Architect** – Plunders Inc, Remote — Mar 2023 - Present

- Develop tools, prefabs, Scriptable objects, and functionality within **Unity** using **C#**. The tools streamlined implementation of components by Game Designers, Artists, and Sound Engineers on Hyper Bimbo Beats and Al Dente.
- Built cross platform functionality using Unity packages like input manager that allowed for games to be released for mobile, web, and PC.
- Created Beat Management architecture in Unity for Rhythm game Hyper Bimbo Beats. The Beat Manager allowed mapping of animations and movement to the beat of a song.

Software Developer: Unity – Clothing Tech LLC, Austin, TX — May 2020 - May 2023

- Developed **UI** (user-interface) and 3D functionality through **Unity**, **C**#, and the **Model-View-Controller** for the released Garment Digital Twin product. This allows for complex data and interactions to be translated to a user friendly interface.
- Worked with Shader Graph to improve the quality of textures that allowed for realistic fabric textures...
- Collaborated on User Interface for mobile and web applications with UX Designer in Figma. These implementations of UI in Unreal and
 Unity let users verifying how a garment fits on avatars representing various sizes.
- Led conversion of Managed C# into Native C++ that allows for the garment data to work with web services. Unreal, and Unity.

Game Developer: Freelance, Unity - Shadow Keep Studios, New York, NY — Jan 2011 - Apr 2012

- Programmed game mechanics, animation, and user interface for the released Unity mobile game Mutton Math.
- Generated builds on the game Mutton Math for **Android** and **iOS** to be released on mobile storefronts.
- Created web builds in **Unity** for Mutton Math that streamlined playtesting by allowing access to the game over the internet.

Quality Assurance Lead – XS Games, New York, NY — *Apr 2008 - Mar 2012*

- Communicated with developers using **Jira** and other bug tracking systems that allowed for prioritization of bugs across 20 shipped titles.
- Trained testers on **Technical Requirements** guidelines for **Nintendo** and **Sony** titles such as The Red Star for PlayStation Portable.
- Developed test plans with test cases for Junior Quality Assurance (QA) Analysts to prevent showstopping bugs for over 20 submissions.

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE:

Software Engineer: Automation – Eveview Digital, Austin, TX (Remote) — Oct 2014 - Jan 2020

Contributing Writer: Gaming – DualShockers, New York, NY — May 2012 - Mar 2013

Onboarding Engineer - Sony DADC, New York, NY — Mar 2012 - May 2013

EDUCATION:

- Computer Science. Master of Science Pace University. White Plains. NY
- Level 3 Publish Indie Game Academy 2023
- Unity Certified User: Programmer Certification Unity Technologies 2020
- Computer Science & Art: Graphics, Bachelor of Arts Manhattanville College, Purchase, NY